[Music]
welcome to the busy Central Louch event
and our session about using of enforced
digital vouches in bu Central where my
colleague Arthur and I will try to
explain in which situation you can use
it as well as how to use and not to be
surprised with some of uh new
features uh agenda is really short for
today we will make some introduction to
understand the background for this
effort and after that we will show how
you can activate the feature and how to
set up to work properly and of course
some examples how it works in a
practice okay let's
start first introduction about vouchers
and especially digital vouchers in the
accounting
World in accounting a voucher is a
document or record that provides
evidence of financial
transaction voucher servers support
documentation for various Financial
activities and there are different types
of vouchers used in accounting each
serving specific purpose for example uh
receip vouchers payment vou ERS credit
or debit voucher purchase or sales
voucher so on so
on now about digital vouchers in
accounting it refers to electronic or
digital documents that serves as the
evidence of financial transactions you
can see only this small difference this
is electronic or digital document it is
essential the electronic equivalent of
traditional paper vouter received and it
help us providing Full O detail using
this way it can help companies to be
more efficient and being in paperless
manner as I explained earlier it can be
applicable uh to different type of
documents and how you will use the force
of digital vouchers it is only on your
company rules except there are
requirements by authorities so you must
behave related with them in digital age
it is more and more desirable to have
even if this is not enforced by the law
but uh this is something we can expect
uh to come from more and more countries
that new that new countries will afford
digital vouchers to prevent frauds and
easier get full DET Trail this complete
approach can even help us and why how
even in some situations where users must
upload documentation there are many
places where document can be created
from records you have in your system so
we cannot we cannot we can uh automate
creation and of digital vouchers and
automatically attach them from the
moment when they created to the record
without any manual work and now what is
difference uh uh between attachments in
digital vouchers and why we are talking
about digital vouchers as we already
have attachments in a busy
Cent what is difference here in general
the main difference is that attachments
are based on voluntary usage and they
can be used on many places not only
connected with accounting many many
different places you can use on customer
card or job card many many different
places on the other side digital
vouchers are accounting category and in
bus Central if you set up they will be
mandatory for specific type of documents
so users don't have an option if they
want or do not want to attach them and
as I mentioned a couple times it can
help providing full paperless OD Trail
in accounting as you can choose for
which documents or journals you want to
enforce usage
and yes as I already said we added great
automation where it is possible to
automatically create digital vouches
based on transaction
type uh this idea came uh from Danish
authori requirements with their new
bookkeeping act but this is um this this
feature can be used in other countries
as well so we decided to create this app
as a global app this is on user to
decide to activate on to configure where
to enforce digital voucher if they want
it at all now let's make close
look to enable this functionality you
will have guided visard to enable it
during this process you can set up
entries you want to use there are
different entry types you can choose to
set up such as sales documents purchase
documents or few different types of
journals and for each of these entries
you can choose what kind of control you
want to configure by control we are
thinking about enforcing if you choose
no check to keep it out of control so
vouchers will not be enforced
attachments is only digital file is
acceptable as a aboutou that that means
you must attach some of files then
attachments plus invoice the same is
previous but adding electronic document
as well and attachment or note that
means you have an OP to upload a file or
if you do not want to use file just to
add some note for this
record that means you can control
whatever you want if you don't want to
use vouchers somewhere you can just
easily uh choose no check if you want to
use vouchers you need to choose one of
three additional options and to clarify
setup depends on what users want or
companies wants except in Denmark where
users cannot disable enforcing mandatory
vouchers in purchase and sales
transactions from January next next
year okay when you uh set up enforcing
except for check type you have two
additional important options for each of
entries you can choose an option gener
generate automatically if digital
vouchers needs to be generated
automatically this is for example
especially big help in sales documents
that means when you post your sales inv
voice system will automatically create
sales invoice document and attach it to
this
transaction but you can also choose skip
if manually added option with enabling
this option the automatically generated
digital voucher will not be added to the
record if menual attachments has already
been added this is on users how they
want to use this option that means even
if this is uh something automatically
created if you decide to to manually
upload it can be your choice you can
choose if if you want to keep both of
these documents on only manually
added and to add one more option you saw
previously five anti types where you can
enforce users and maybe you can say this
is not enough to provide full choice for
some specific documents where you want
to use but not to all this is especially
case in
journals because you can use journals in
various uh different situations so
because of that we added additional
setup where you can add specific source
code for enforcing so now you can for
example enforce users to have digital
vouchers in general journal but only if
the source code is for example payroll
or something
similar okay I think demo speaks better
than thousands words so my colleague
Arthur will show you how it works in a
practice
Arthur I'm going to cover three
scenarios uh as Alexandra explained from
the setup uh we going to have a setup
for the sales document the check type
will be attachment and I have it
generate automatically it means that if
there is no attachment by the user I'm
going to generate uh uh this report
automatically for the purchase document
we have the check type of attachment and
that means that the user has to attach
the document and then the third scenario
will be says Journal when we don't have
any check so if user do not attach any
digital voucher he still will be able to
pause the document let's start with the
purchase
document I'm going to create a new
invoice specify all the necessary
fields and then I will try to pause the
the document without attaching any
digital
voucher and when I do this I can see the
error message that it's not possible to
post without attaching the digital
voucher so in order to post I need to go
to the incommon document files F box and
click attach
file here I need to select file from my
local
box I can see the file attached and then
I can continue with
posting the document is posted
now and I can see my file attached in
the incoming document files tag box and
also I can see my file connected to the
Gen general ledger entry so I go to
theine entries general ledger entry and
I can see still can see the same F box
in common document files and this file
will be connected to every single G
entry let's now try to do the same with
the sales
invoice I want to create a new sales
invoice and then I I don't want to
attach any document but I want them to
create automatically so when I pause the
document I would not see any error
message and the document is posted
successfully but where is my digital
voucher and the digital voucher is
attached to the coming document file and
when I open the digital
voucher I can see that this is the
report automatically generated for this
one and attached to posted sales inv
voice and in the same way like for
purchas invoice I can see that the
digital voucher is connected to GL
entry for every single GL
entry and the latest scenario that will
be covered is the sales journal for the
sales Journal I don't have uh a setup
that enforces me to attach digital
voucher so if I go to the S journal and
if I want to
create an invoice for the
customer and I want to post this
invoice without attaching any do
document there will be no error so I can
post the document without digital
vulture Alexander
okay thank you Arthur this great demo
and this is shortly what we wanted to
show you for it uh these features now I
would like to say thank you for watching
this
um uh uh session about uh enforcing
digital vouchers and BC lunch event uh
we will be in a date of B Lun when both
of us will be there so we'll be open for
questions answer so you can ask us
everything what is not so clear from
this presentation before we finish for
today I would like to invite you for
some additional uh sessions somehow
connected with uh this topic one of them
is what is new related with new Danish
bookie Pig act because this feature will
be one part of uh all requirement for
Danish booking acts and what is new
legislation localization in busy Central
and again before finish uh if you are
missing some of information for busy
Central just go to some of these uh
links and you can find many interesting
things if you cannot uh remember all of
them minimum try to not to forget AK
msbc all so you can find all these
important links there once more thank
you and my and
name